ldslinkup.com 2013-05-19

# LDS LinkUp Privacy Policy

** LDS LINKUP PRIVACY POLICY**

**LDS LinkUp** values your privacy.  The following Privacy Statement describes our privacy practices.

**LDS LINKUP PRIVACY STATEMENT**

WHO NEW LLC (“Who New LLC”) owns and operates online networking web sites, including [www.ldslinkup.com](http://www.ldslinkup.com/) ("LDS LinkUp").  Because we value our users' privacy and want to demonstrate our commitment to protecting it, we are disclosing our information and privacy practices. This privacy statement discloses and describes the privacy practices of the website [www.ldslinkup.com](http://www.ldslinkup.com/).   

  * About Who New and its use of information
  * What information LDS LinkUp collects
  * How LDS LinkUp uses information
  * With whom LDS LinkUp shares information
  * User choices regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  * Security procedures in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under LDS LinkUp control
  * How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information
  * How LDS LinkUp will notify users of changes to its Privacy Statement

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should send an email to [privacypolicy@ldslinkup.com](mailto:privacypolicy@ldslinkup.com).

LDS LinkUp is an online community that allows its members to post personal profiles and to browse or search personal profiles posted by others in order to identify and contact new people they might want to meet.  The profiles can contain personal information about, among other things, a member's appearance, ethnicity, profession, religion, and interests.  The profiles may also contain photographs.  Collecting this information from members and providing services that enable members to search or browse through such profiles is fundamental to LDS LinkUp's business. 

At the same time, LDS LinkUp is dedicated to protecting its members' privacy.  LDS LinkUp is designed to give its members more control over their personal information, including their LDS LinkUp profiles, than traditional online dating services.  Through its "Visibility Preference" setting, LDS LinkUp allows each member choice as to who can see his or her personal profile.  In particular, LDS LinkUp allows each member to restrict viewership of his or her profile to LDS LinkUp members only, or, if he or she wishes, to all website visitors.

Who New LLC is the sole owner of the information collected on [www.ldslinkup.com](http://www.ldslinkup.com/). 

## Links

The LDS LinkUp web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that LDS LinkUp is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.  We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.  This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.  

### Third Party Advertising

Advertisements appearing on [www.ldslinkup.com](http://www.ldslinkup.com/) may be delivered to users by external advertising partners or networks.  In that event, information about users’ visits to the site, such as number of times they have viewed an ad (but not the user's name, email address, or other Personally Identifying Information), may be used to serve appropriate advertisements.  In most cases, third-party advertising networks will use cookie technology to deliver relevant ads.  Some or all of our third-party advertising networks may belong to the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), which provides users the opportunity to opt out of their cookie program.  For more information please visit the NAI's [ opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Please note that this privacy statement covers the practices of LDS LinkUp and does not cover the practices any advertisers or other business partners.  Also note that this privacy statement covers information collected by LDS LinkUp; it does not cover information users give directly to advertisers or other business partners. 

LDS LinkUp collects six types of information about its users:

  * **ID and contact information** \- Includes Members' names and email addresses.
  * **Profile Information (excluding photographs)** \- Includes information supplied by each Member for his or her personal LDS LinkUp profile. Profiles may include information on member's appearance, ethnicity, profession, religion, interests, and other descriptive information provided by the Member.  It may also include information about what the Member is looking for in a potential match.  LDS LinkUp may supplement this information in a Member's profile with limited _activity information_ , for example, when a Member joined LDS LinkUp or how recently the Member has logged in to LDS LinkUp.  Note that LDS LinkUp prohibits inclusion of Personally Identifying Information (see below) other than photographs in its profiles.

  * **Photographs** \- Includes photographs uploaded or otherwise transmitted by Members as part of their LDS LinkUp profiles.

  * **Messaging Information** \- Includes the text, sender, addressee, and time sent of email messages sent through the LDS LinkUp email system.  These messages include invitations to join LDS LinkUp and messages to other Who New members who may be potential matches. 

  * **Discussion Information** \- Includes the text, poster, and time sent of discussion board messages posted to the LDS LinkUp discussion board system. 

  * **Billing Information** \- Includes credit card and billing address information necessary to complete credit card transactions to pay for LDS LinkUp services.

  * **Activity Information** \- Includes information about how a user uses the LDS LinkUp website and service, for example, which pages are visited, which services are used, when a user joined LDS LinkUp, when a user last logged in to LDS LinkUp, etc.  Activity information may also include how a user came to LDS LinkUp, including promotion codes, etc.

### Where LDS LinkUp Collects Information

LDS LinkUp collects this information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

#### _Sign-Up _

To become a member, a user must provide _ID and contact information_ to enable LDS LinkUp to create a unique member ID for him or her.  During sign-up, new members are also encouraged to begin creating their personal profiles and to invite friends to join LDS LinkUp. 

Because of LDS LinkUp's model, non-members cannot view LDS LinkUp's member profiles, unless members have explicitly chosen to make their profiles visible to non-members.

####  _Edit Your Profile/Preferences_

Once a member has joined LDS LinkUp, he can edit his personal profile, post or unpost his profile, or change his account preferences at any time. 

## _Subscription_

If a member decides to subscribe to paid LDS LinkUp services, we will request _billing information_ from the member via our subscription form.  At that point, the member must provide billing name and address information and payment information (such as credit card number, expiration date, etc.) needed to complete the transaction.  Because LDS LinkUp subscriptions typically renew automatically, LDS LinkUp typically stores billing information to allow renewal transactions.

## _Invitation/Messaging_

When a member invites a friend to join LDS LinkUp or sends a message through the LDS LinkUp system to another LDS LinkUp member, LDS LinkUp collects the text and the addressee of the message.  When a member invites a friend, LDS LinkUp also collects the friend’s name and email address and sends an email inviting the friend to visit the site.  LDS LinkUp stores the friend's information for the sole purpose of sending this email and one or more follow up emails and tracking the success of our referral program.  The friend may contact LDS LinkUp at removeme@ldslinkup.com to request the removal of his name and email address from our database.

## _Discussion Boards_

When a member posts a message to an LDS LinkUp discussion board, LDS LinkUp collects the text and the posting time of the message, for the purpose of displaying the message on the indicated discussion board.  Except where explicitly stated on the site, LDS LinkUp does not allow members to remove posts once they have been posted.

## _Other Activities_

When a member or other visitor visits the LDS LinkUp web site, LDS LinkUp may collect _activity information_ about the member's activities, such as how often he visits, which pages he visits, and which LDS LinkUp services he uses.  This information is used for improving the LDS LinkUp web site and service offering and for refining our marketing programs.

## How LDS LinkUp Collects Information

## Besides asking its users to provide information for their profile or for billing purposes, LDS LinkUp uses, or may in the future use, several different technologies (including cookies, log files, and clear gifs) to collect and track _activity information_.

## _Cookies_

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user.  There are two types of cookies, temporary cookies, which disappear when the user is inactive for a period of time (typically 10-20 minutes) or when he closes his browser, and persistent cookies, which are stored for a longer period.  A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help directions.

LDS LinkUp uses temporary cookies to manage user sessions and to prevent unauthorized users from viewing member profiles.  LDS LinkUp uses persistent cookies to remember a user's login information so that, if a user wishes, he can return to site after a period of time without having to retype his login email and password.  Because controlling access to member profiles is central to LDS LinkUp's offering, users who reject all cookies will not be able to use the member areas of our site.   

In the future, LDS LinkUp business partners (for example, advertisers) may use cookies on our site.  Although LDS LinkUp will review each partner's privacy policy prior to agreeing to allow cookies,  LDS LinkUp will have no access to or control over these cookies once we have given a partner permission to set them. 

### _Log Files_

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files.  These files collect user internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser types, internet service providers (ISPs), referring/exit pages, platform types, date/time stamps, and click counters, among other date.  This data is used to analyze trends, administer the site, identify technical problems, track users' movements in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.    

We, or our business partners, may also employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage the content of our site our our communications with our members. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier that let us know when particular pages or emails are accessed by users.  

Clear Gifs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same Web site or advertising company.  That means, for example, that if a person visited “www.companyX.com”, which uses an advertising company's clear gif, the Web site or advertising company could match the clear gif's identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. This collected information would then be given to the advertising company or Web site.  At present, LDS LinkUp does not use clear gifs in this way.

In addition, we may use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients.  This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

##  Supplemental Information

In order for LDS LinkUp to deliver the highest quality services to its users, we may decide to supplement the information we gather via our web site with information from 3rd party sources.  At this time, LDS LinkUp does not use information from such external sources.

## Personally Identifying Information

In the course of its business, LDS LinkUp collects information that identifies particular Members (Personally Identifying Information).  Of the seven types of information LDS LinkUp collects, five are Personally Identifying Information:  ID and Contact Information, Photographs, Messaging Information, Discussion Information, and Billing Information.  See below for LDS LinkUp's policy on sharing Personally Identifying Information.

LDS LinkUp's uses of information depend on the category of information: ID/contact information, profile information, messaging information, discussion information, billing information, or activity information.  In addition to the primary uses described below, LDS LinkUp may use information for other purposes including, but not restricted to, investigating user complaints, enforcing our Online Conduct standards (see our Terms of Service), or communicating with law enforcement.

### _Identification and Contact Information_

We use Members' ID and contact information to

  * create a unique Member ID that we use to allow Members to log in to Members-only areas of the site and to ensure that each Member can view appropriate profiles from other Members and control who views his or her own profile

  * facilitate (or block) anonymous email communication between Members so that Members can exchange messages with potential matches without divulging their contact information

  * communicate with our Members regarding the status of their LDS LinkUp Membership and LDS LinkUp services.  Note that Members can opt out of receiving promotional communications.

### _Profile Information (excluding photos)_

We use profile information users provide about themselves and what they are seeking in a match

  * in Members' personal profiles.  Each Member can view or edit his profile at any time

  * to match specific profiles with searches done by other Members looking for potential matches with particular characteristics

  * to match specific new profiles with LDS LinkUp Agent criteria set by Members who want to be notified when new Members with particular characteristics join LDS LinkUp

Please note that which Who New users can view a Member's profile is determined by a) whether the Member and the user are "connected," i.e., part of the same LDS LinkUp group, b) whether the user is a LDS LinkUp Member, and c) the "Visibility Preference" setting of the profile Member.  Members can change their Visibility Preference at any time to exercise a measure of control over who views their profile.

### _Photographs_

We use Members' photographs as part of their personal profiles.

### _Messaging Information_

We use the text and addressee information of invitation emails sent a) to invite people to join LDS LinkUp and b) between  LDS LinkUp members to

  * allow members to review messages they have sent and received

  * analyze which invitation email text is most effective in getting invitees to join

### _Discussion Information_

We use _discussion information_ collected to provide discussion board services to our members.

### _Billing Information_

We use _billing information_ collected from our members to execute payments for LDS LinkUp subscription services.

### _Activity Information_

We use activity information to improve LDS LinkUp's web site, service offerings, and marketing programs by, among other things,

  * tracking how users move through the site
  * measuring which functions are more or less popular
  * determining which marketing messages are most effective in communicating LDS LinkUp's value proposition to potential members

**Communications from LDS LinkUp**

## _Special Offers and Updates_

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

_**Service Announcements**_

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement.  For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email.  Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account.  However, these communications are not promotional in nature. 

## _Customer Service_

We communicate by email with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and regarding account issues.

LDS LinkUp does not rent, sell, or share Personally Identifying Information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies except a) to provide products or services you've requested, b) when we have asked for and received your permission, or c) under the following circumstances: 

  * We provide the information to trusted partners who work on behalf of or with LDS LinkUp under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your information to help LDS LinkUp communicate with you about offers from LDS LinkUp and our marketing partners. However, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information. 

  * We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; 

  * We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of LDS LinkUp's Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law

  * We transfer information about you if LDS LinkUp is acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, LDS LinkUp will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

## Third Party Advertisers

LDS LinkUp from time to time shares (not Personally Identifying) Activity Information about its users with reputable third parties for the purpose of targeting Internet advertisements on this site and other sites. 

## Aggregate Information

LDS LinkUp from time to time shares aggregated information (not Personally Identifying) about our users with business partners and advertisers. 

LDS LinkUp gathers Activity Information on users who visit LDS LinkUp's web site but do not join.  Invitees who choose not to join LDS LinkUp can request the removal of their ID and Contact Information from LDS LinkUp's database (see below).  With the exception of ID and Contact Information, which they are required to provide, and Activity Information, which is collected automatically, users who join LDS LinkUp and become Members can provide as much or as little information as they wish when solicited at LDS LinkUp's web site.  Members can also choose not to post a LDS LinkUp profile or to take down their profile at any time after it is posted.

In addition, LDS LinkUp gives its members the following options for controlling their personal information.  Members can edit these preferences at www.ldslinkup.com/members/edit_account_preferences.asp.

## Visibility Preference

LDS LinkUp members can exercise a measure of control over who can view their LDS LinkUp profile by adjusting their "Visibility Preference."  This allows members to make their profile visible just to LDS LinkUp members or to all LDS LinkUp visitors, including non-Members.

## Opt-out from LDS LinkUp Promotional Messages

Members who do not wish to receive update and promotional messages may opt-out of receiving these communications by changing their Promotional Email Preference at the address given above. 

## Make Membership Inactive

LDS LinkUp members can at any time make their membership inactive.  This takes down their LDS LinkUp profile and opts the member out of receiving update messages.  The member also can no longer use most of LDS LinkUp' functionality.  Note that personal information of inactive members may be retained in LDS LinkUp's database

## Request Removal of Information

Members who decide to leave LDS LinkUp or invitees who choose not to join can request that their name and email address actually be removed from LDS LinkUp's database by sending an email from their email address of record to [ CustomerService@ldslinkup.com  Subject: Remove Me](mailto:CustomerService@ldslinkup.com?subject=Remove%20Me).

####  Security Procedures in Place to Protect the Loss, Misuse or Alteration of Information Under LDS LinkUp Control

LDS LinkUp is committed to keeping our Members' information secure and we've taken steps to protect sensitive information both online and offline.

**ID/Contact and Profile Information**

Users who are not LDS LinkUp Members do not have access to LDS LinkUp Member profiles, except for those profiles where a Member has specifically chosen to have his or her profile visible to all LDS LinkUp visitors/users.  Otherwise, LDS LinkUp requires to become Members and to log in to use LDS LinkUp's Service, including viewing other Members' profiles or viewing/editing their own personal information.  Each Members-only page checks that the Member is logged in and that the Member has permission to view the page in question.  LDS LinkUp uses a combination of cookies and other technologies to enforce that only permitted viewers can view sensitive LDS LinkUp content.

**Billing Information**

When our subscription/order form asks Members to enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number or billing address), that information is encrypted and protected with industry-standard, 128-bit SSL technology.  While on a secure page, the lock icon on the bottom of web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer is locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are on a normal page. Credit card numbers that are stored in our database are encrypted using sophisticated encryption algorithms.

**Offline Security**

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also work to protect user-information offline.  All of our Members’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices.  Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, a billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to Personally Identifying Information. 

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to [ CustomerService@ldslinkup.com Subject: Security](mailto:customerservice@ldslinkup.com?subject=Security) .

If a member’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), the member can update the information at any time at www.ldslinkup.com/members/edit.asp.  If a member no longer wants to use our service, he can render his membership inactive at the Member Preferences page (www.ldslinkup.com/members/edit_account_preferences.asp).  If a member wants to delete all his name and email address from our system, he can send an email request to [ CustomerService@ldslinkup.com  Subject: Remove Me](mailto:CustomerService@ldslinkup.com?subject=Remove%20Me). This email must me sent from his currently active LDS LinkUp email address.

If LDS LinkUp decides to change our privacy policy, we will notify our Members by posting the changes to this Privacy Statement.  We may also post notice of the changes to our homepage and/or other places we believe are appropriate. 

Unless we have Members' explicit consent, we will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.  If, however, we plan to use Members’ Personally Identifying Information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, Members will be offered a choice (via email to their currently active LDS LinkUp email address) as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner.  Members who have resigned their membership or otherwise been removed from our system will not be contacted, and their Personally Identifying Information will not be used in this new manner.

## Contact Information

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please email us at [privacypolicy@ldslinkup.com](mailto:privacypolicy@ldslinkup.com), or mail us at

LDS LinkUp Privacy Policy

3450 Sacramento St. #300

San Francisco, CA  94118

LDS LinkUp Privacy Statement Version 1.6
